Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace pamphlet and microfilm collection, 1817-1950 MS2110
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Unbound pamphlets, 1817-1950; MS2110 Series 2; 47 Linear feet
  - "La Doctrine Drago" ["The Drago Doctrine"] (Box 37, Folder 50)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-82, Author: Holguin, Jorge [Conference at the Hague?]
  - "Responsibility for the War and for the Treaty of Trianon", 1928 (Box 37, Folder 51)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-83, Author: Horvath, Eugene [Publications of the Hungarian Frontier Readjustment League]
  - "Discourse De M. Hymans En Response A M. Motta, President De La Confederation Suisse" ["Speech of M. Hymans in Reply to M. Motta President of the Swiss Confederation"], 1923 ca. (Box 37, Folder 52)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-84, Author: Hymans, M.
  - "L'Allemnagne et le Droit des Gens" ["Germany and Human Rights"], 1915 (Box 37, Folder 53)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-85, Author: Imprimene des Journalux Officiels
  - "L'Allemnagne et le Droit des Gens" ["Germany and Human Rights"], 1915 (Box 37, Folder 54)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-86, Author: Imprimene des Journalux Officiels [Press for Official Journals]
  - "La Situation De La Femme Mariee Dans L'Enseignement" ["The Situation of the Married Woman in Teaching"], 1933 (Box 37, Folder 55)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-87, Author: International Bureau of Education
  - "Accords De Compensation" "Kompensationsabkommen" [Clearing Agreemnets], 1936 (Box 37, Folder 56)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-88, Author: International Chamber of Commerce
  - "Catalogue D'Ouvrages Sur La Paix Et La Guerre" ["Catalog of Works on Peace and War"], 1901 (Box 37, Folder 57)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-89, Author: International Peace Bureau
  - "Le Comite Directeur du Bureau International de la Paix dans les Balkans" ["The Governing Committee fo the International Bureau for Peace in the Balkans" (13 to 30 October 1929)] (Box 37, Folder 58)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-90, Author: International Peace Bureau, Geneva (Switzerland)
  - "Rapport Du Conseil Interparlementaire A La Conference" Interparliamentary Union XVIIIth Conference, Teneva, 18-20 Sept. 1912 ["Report of the Interparliamentary Council to the Conference"] (Box 37, Folder 59)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-91, Author: Interparliamentary Union
  - "La Societe Des Naitons Et Le Probleme Fondamental De L'Organisation International" ["The League of Nations and the Fundamental Problem of the International Organization"], 1933 (Box 37, Folder 60)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-92, Author: Jascenka, A.
  - "La Societe des Nations et le Probleme Fondamental..." ["The League of Nations and the Fundamentale problem of the International Organization"], 1933 (Box 37, Folder 61)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-93, Author: Jascenko, A.
  - "Les Deux Methodes" ["The Two Methods" Conference by Jean Jaures and Jules Guesde], 1900 (Box 37, Folder 62)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-94, Author: Jaures, Jean and Jules Guesede
  - "L'Action du Parti Socialiste" ["Action of the Socialist Party"], 1908 (Box 37, Folder 63)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-95, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "La Protestation du Droit" ["The Protest the Right"], 1911 (Box 37, Folder 64)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-96, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Pour la Laique" ["For Secular Schools"], 1910 (Box 37, Folder 65)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-97, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Politique d'Aviner" ["Politics of the Future"], 1909 (Box 37, Folder 66)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-98, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "L'Action Syndicale et le Parti Socialsite" ["Trade-Union Action and the Socialist Party"], 1912 (Box 37, Folder 67)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-99, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Contre l'Emprunt et le Deficit" ["Against Borrowing and the Deficit"], 1913 (Box 37, Folder 68)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-100, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Discours a la Jeunesse" ["Speech to the Youth"], 1903 (Box 37, Folder 69)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-101, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Le Parti Socialiste et la Cirse Postale" ["The Socialist Party and the Postal Crisis"], 1909 (Box 37, Folder 70)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-102, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Idealisme et Materialisme dans la Conception de l'Histoire" ["Idealism and Materialism in the Conception of History"], 1901 (Box 37, Folder 71)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-103, Author: Jaures, Jean
  - "Juges Par Eux-Memes Paroles Allemandes" ["Judged by Themselves" "German Words" Preface by Whitney-Warren], 1916 (Box 37, Folder 72)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-104
  - "Proposition: Pour Etablir Une Cour Economique International" ["Proposal to Establish an International Economic Court"], 1928 (Box 37, Folder 73)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-105, Author: Keleman, Sandor
  - "Why the Nationalsists International?", 1936 (Box 37, Folder 74 item 1)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-106, Author: Keller, Hans K.E.L.
  - "L'Internationale Ennemie Des Nations", 1936 (Box 37, Folder 74 item 2)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-106, Author: Bertarand, Louis
  - "Les Bolcheviks" ["The Bolsheviks"], 1918 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-107, Author: La Chesnais, P.G.
  - "Le Probleme Ethnographique du Banaf" ["The Ethnographic Problems of Banat with Four Statistical Tables and a Map of Banat" [a Rumaniaovince], 1919 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-108, Author: Lalesco, Trajan
  - "Requete" ["Request of thh Large German Property Owners of the Czechoslovak Republic, Concerning the Confiscation of Their Property, Anticipated for 1 January 1923, Addressed to the League of Nations"], 1922 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-109, Author: La Ligue Allemande de Republique Tchecoslovaque pour la Societe des Nations [The German League of the Czechoslovak Republic for the League of Nations]
  - "Les Suisses et Les Dommages de Guerre" ["The Swiss and War Damages"], 1932 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-110, Author: Lapradelle, A.G. [Les Editions Internationales]
  - "Un Aspect du Droit a la REparation des Domages de Guerre" ["A Look at teh Right to REaprations of War Damages"], 1932 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-111, Author: Lapradelle, Albrt Geouffre de [Les Editions Internationales]
  - "Le Livre d'Or Faculie de Droit de Paris (France), Guerre 1914-1918" ["The Gold Book of the Faculty of Law of Paris (France)" War 1914-1918], 1925 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-112, Author: Larnaude, Ferdinand
  - "Les Sciences Jurisdiques and Politiques" ["The Juridical and Political Sciences"], 1910 ca. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-113, Author: Larnaude, F.
  - "Alfred Nobel-Notice Biographique" ["Alfred Nobel: Biographic Note"], 1910 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-114, Author: Larsson, Emile
  - "L'Association Universelle des Enfants" ["The Universal Association of Children"], 1944 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-115, Author: Lauterer, Karla [New League of Nations Proposal for a Great Universal Effort for Peace]
  - "La Guerre et la Politique du Paris (France) Socialiste Francais" ["The War and the Policy of the french Socialist Party"], 1916 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-116, Author: Lebas, J. [Edition de l'Avenir, Revue de Socialisme]
  - "Probite Scientifique" ["Scientific Integrity"], 1923 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-117, Author: Lecat, Maurice
  - "La Societe des Nations el l'Union des Associations Internationales" ["Memorandum by the Secretary General of the League of Nations"], 1926 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-118, Author: League of Nations-Societe des Nations
  - "Hommage a la Mission Universitaire Francaise" ["Hommage to the French University Mission"], 1924 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-119, Author: Leao, A. Carneiro ["Rio"]
  - "Liverte de l'Etat et Bien Commun International" ["Liberty of the State of Common International Good"], 1939 ca. (Box 38, Folder 14)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-120, Author: Le Fur, Louis
  - "La Societe Des Naitons" ["The League of Nations and the Current Crisis"], 1934 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-121, Author: Le Fur, Louis
  - "Revue Metaphusique et de Morale" [Review of Metaphysics and Ethics "State, International Community and League of Nations"], 1923 ca. (Box 38, Folder 16)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-122, Author: Le Fur, Louis
  - "Jean Jaures" ["Jean Jaures"], 1915 ca. (Box 38, Folder 17)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-123, Author: Legand, Rene
  - "Les Buts d'Allemagne Announces par les auteurs Allemands" ["German Goals Announced by German Authors"], 1917 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-124, Author:
  - "L'Institute International des Sciences Adminidtratives", 1948 ca. (Box 38, Folder 19)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-125, Author: Lesoir, Edmond and Daniel Warnotte
  - "La Paix par la Justice" ["Peace Through Justice"], 1929 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-126, Author: Levy, Emmanuel
  - "La Conflagration Europeene" ["The Europena Conflagration: It's Economic and Political Causes"], 1915 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-127, Author: Levy-Bruhl, L.
  - "Quelques Pages sur Jean Jaures" ["Some Pages on Jean Jaures"], 1916 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-128, Author: Levy-Bruhl, Lucien
  - "L'Organisation de la Societe des Naitons" ["The Organizaiton of the League of Naitons"], 1917 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-129, Author: Ligue des Droits de L'Homme et du Citoyen [The Lague of the Rights of Man and of the Citizens] [Buisson, Ferdinand, Jean Hennesy, Maxime Leroy, Victor Basch, Th. Ruyssen, Paul Otlet, d'Estournelles de Constant, Et. Fournoi]
  - "La Difference Enter l'Arbitrage International et la Justice International" ["The Difference Between International Arbitration and International Justice"], 1923 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-130, Author: Loder, Dr. B.C.J.
  - "Discours Presidentiel" ["Presidential Speech Given on the Occasion of the Solemn Opening of the Permanent Court of International Justice"], 1922 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-131, Author: Loder, B.C.J.
  - "Vers La Societe des Nations" ["Toward the League of Nations"], 1919 ca. (Box 38, Folder 26)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-132, Author: L'Oevre [Work]
  - "A la Recherche d'un Ideal Universal" ["In Search of a Universal Ideal"], 1939 ca. (Box 38, Folder 27)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-133, Author: Malan, Bern (Switzerland) ard
  - "Memoire Sur la Delimitation des Droits de l'Etat et de la Nation" ["Report on the Demarcation of the Rights of the State and of the Naiton According to President Wilson"], 1919 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-134, Author: Mandelstram, Andre
  - "Pour da Liberte, L'Egalite et la Fraternite" ["For Liberty, Equality, and Fraternity"], 1930 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-135, Author: Milic, Dusan [Scenario for a film in Six Acts]
  - "Comment Se Fera Le Desarmement" ["How Disarmament will Take Place"], 1897 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-137, Author: Moch, Gaston
  - "La Garantie de la Societe des Nations" ["The Guaranty of the League of Nations"], 1916 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-138, Author: Moch, Gaston
  - "Le Bresil et la Crise de la Societe des Nations" ["Brazil and the Crisis of the League of Nations in 1926"] (Box 38, Folder 32)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-139, Author: Montarroyos, E.
  - "Livre Pacifiste A L'Usage De La Juenesse" ["Pacifist Book to be used by Youth"], 1911 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-140, Author: Muller, Arthur [Ronse (Belgium) ?]
  - "Le Droit Polonaism au Service de la Paix dans la lutte Contre les Criminels de Guerre" ["Polish Law in Service of Peace in the Fight Against War Criminals"], 1947 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-141, Author: Muszlat, Cyprian Sawichi [Polish Service for Research on War Criminals]
  - "Deuxieme Assemblee de la Societe Des Nations: Propositions D'Amendments Aux Articles 18 & 26 Du Pacte", 1924 (Box 38, Folder 35)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-142, Author: Negulesco, Demetre
  - "La Croix-Rouge Et La Paix" ["The Red Cross and the Peace"], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 36)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-143, Author: Ningawa, Arata [part in English]
  - "La Ligue des Nations" ["The League of Nations"], 1918 (Box 38, Folder 37)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-144, Author: Nippold, Otfried
  - "Foundation Nobel" ["Nobel Foundation Statute and Regulation"], 1900 (Box 38, Folder 38)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-145, Author: Nobel Stiftelsen
  - L'Arbitrage en Droit International Deuxieme Partie-La Cour Permanente d'Arbitrage et de Jurisprudence ["Arbitration in International Law, Part Two: The Permanent Court of Arbitration and Jurisprudence"], 1946 (Box 38, Folder 39)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-146, "Notes Documentaires et Etudes
  - "Congres Mondial Des Associations Internationales" ["World Congress of International Associations"], 1913 (Box 38, Folder 40)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-147, Author: Office Central Des Associations Internationales [Central Office of International Associations]
  - "Congres Mondial des Associations Internatioales" ["World Congress of International Associations"Summary Account of the Second Session], 1913 (Box 38, Folder 41)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-148, Author: Office Central des Associations Internationales
  - "L'Aire et l'Avenir" ["Air and the Future: Considerations on Air Traffic"], 1912 (Box 38, Folder 42)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-149, Author: Office Central des Associations Internationales
  - "Le Musee International" ["The International Museum" Notice-Catalog], 1914 (Box 38, Folder 43)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-150, Author: Office Central Des Associations Internationales
  - "L'Office Central Des Institutions Internationales" ["The Center Office of International Institutions" [Its Organizaiton, Its Services, Its Work], 1911 (Box 38, Folder 44)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-151, Author: Office Central Des Institutions Internationales
  - "Le Regime des Associations Internaitonales" ["The Governance of International Associations:], 1912 ca. (Box 38, Folder 45)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-152, Author: Office Central Des Associations Internationals
  - "Le Devori des Neutres" ["The Duty of the Neutrals"], 1915 (Box 38, Folder 46)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-153, Author: Organisation Neerlandaise pour une Paix Durable [Netherland Association for a Lasting Peace]
  - "Sur l'Etablissement en Belgique du Siege de la Societe des Nations" ["On the Establishment in Belgium of the Headquarters of the League of Nations"], 1919 (Box 38, Folder 47)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-154, Author: Otlet, Paul
  - "La Question Des Iles D'Aland" ["The Question of the Aland Islands"], 1919 (Box 38, Folder 48)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-155, Author: Paris (France) Peace Conference [Volume 1]
  - "Association de la Paix Par Le Droit" ["Association of Peace through Law"] (Box 38, Folder 49)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-156, Author: Passy, Frederic
  - "Les Armements de L'Avenir" ["Armements of the Future"], 1895 (Box 38, Folder 50)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-157, Author: Passy, Frederic [French Society of Arbitration Amoung Naitons]
  - "Appeal aux Elites de Universe..." ["Appeal to the Elites of the Universe..."], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 51)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-158, Author: Paul, Samie de
  - "L'Arbitrage Egyptien-Americain de 1931" ["The Egyptian-American Arbitration of 1931"], 1933 (Box 38, Folder 52)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-159, Author: Pintor, Siotto
  - "L'Institute de Droit Inernationale..." ["The Institute of International Law and the Examination of the Organization and of the Statutes of the League of Nations"], 1923 (Box 38, Folder 53)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-160, Author: Planas-Suarez, Simon
  - "Clemenceau: L'Homme et l'oevre" ["Clemenceau: The Man and the Work"], 1907 (Box 38, Folder 54)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-161, Author: Poinsot, M.-C
  - "The Present Crisis and L'Angoisse Actuelle" ["The Present Crisis or the European Problem"], 1933 (Box 38, Folder 55)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-162, Author: Pointe, James
  - "Pax Vobis ou La Paix par l'Education" ["Peace to You or Peace through Education"], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 56)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-163, Author: Poiny, Isidore
  - "La Politique de L'Avenir Prochain" ["The Politics of the Near Future"] (Box 38, Folder 57)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-164, Author: Polak, Dr. J.
  - "La Societe des Nations et la Securite Collective: ["The League of Naitons and Collective Security"], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 58)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-165, Author: Ponsoby, Lord
  - "Final Report; La Paquet au Front and le Secours Fransaise" ["The Package to the Front and Aid to the Fren1939 ca.-1945"], 1946 (Box 38, Folder 59)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-166, Author: Porter, Mrs. Seton
  - "La Science Politique Dands le Domaine International" ["Political Science in the International Domanin"], 1940 (Box 38, Folder 60)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-167, Author: Potter, B. Pitman
  - "Pour la Paix par l'Ecole" ["For Peace through the School"], 1928 (Box 38, Folder 61)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-168, Author: Prudhommeaux, Jules Jean
  - "Enque te sur les Conditions d'une Paix Durable" ["Inquiry into the Conditions of a Lasting Peace"] (Box 38, Folder 62)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-169, Author: Publications des "Temp Nouveaux" [Publications of "New Times"]
  - "L'Unamite Absolue de Voix, Condition Indespensabel Pour la Revision des Traites dan le Cadre de la S.d.n" ["The Absolute Unanimity of Voices, Indispenable Condition for Revision of Treaties in the Context of the League of Naitons"], 1937 (Box 38, Folder 63)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-170, Author: RamNice (France) ano-Frassine [International Law Review]
  - International Bureau of Education White Paper ["Educaion Reform"] "Reconstruction Educative", 1944 (Box 38, Folder 64)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-171
  - "La Guerre et La Grande Guerre" ["War and the Great War"], 1918 (Box 38, Folder 65)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-172, Author: Reis Carvalho, Antonio
  - "Au Comite Nobel du Parlement Norvegien Oslo" ["To the Nobel Committee of the Norwegian Parliament, Biographical Sketch of Vittorio Scialoja"], 1933 (Box 38, Folder 66)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-173, Author: Riccobono, Salvatore; Benini, Rodolfo; Rocco, Alfredo
  - "Almanach De La Paix" ["Almanac of Peace for 1912"], 1912 ca. (Box 38, Folder 67)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-174, Author: Richet, Charles (author of preface) [The Association fo Peace Through Law]
  - "Pourquoi les Americains Sont Venus en France" ["Why the Americans Came to France"], 1918 (Box 38, Folder 68)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-175, Author: Rodrigues, Gustave
  - "Jaures" ["Jaures"], 1915 (Box 38, Folder 69)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-176, Author: Rolland, Rome (Italy)in
  - "La Sanction du Droit International" ["The Sanction of International Law"], 1908 (Box 38, Folder 70)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-177, Author: Root, Elihu
  - "La Revision du Traite de Trianon est-elle Possible?" ["The Revision of the Treaty of Trianon: Is it Possible?"], 1934 (Box 38, Folder 71)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-178, Author: Rosental, S.
  - "La Conference de la Paix a la Haye" ["The Peace Conference at the Hague"], 1900 (Box 38, Folder 72)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-179, Author: Rousseau, Arthur [F. de Martens]
  - "Sous-Marins et Blocus" ["Submarines and Blockade"], 1917 (Box 38, Folder 73)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-180, Author: Rousseau, A.
  - "La Social-Democratie Alklemande et Austro-Hongroise et les Socialistes Belge" ["The German and Austo-Hungarian Social-Democracy and the Belgian Socialists"], 1914 ca. (Box 38, Folder 74)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-181, Author: Royer, Emile
  - "Principes Politique et Moyens" ["Principles, Policy and Means"], 1935 ca. (Box 38, Folder 75)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-182, Author: Runhambrown, H.
  - "Memories Presentes a Mr. le President de la Conference de Paix" ["Memoranda Presented to the President of the Peace Conference"], 1919 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-183, Author: Sazonow, Prince Lvov; B. Maklakoff
  - "Ce qu'ils Auraient Fait de l'Alsace-Lorraine..." ["What they Would have done with Alsace-Lorraine..."], 1919 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-184, Author: Schmidt, Charles
  - "Le Droit Par La Paix" ["The Law by the Peace"], 1933 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-185, Author: Schuurman, W.H.A.
  - "La Postiono D'Aland" ["The Position fo Aland During the Historical Age"], 1919 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-186, Author: Schybergson, M.G.
  - "La Situation Juridique Des Fonctionnaires" ["The Legal Situation of Government Workers"], 1930 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-187, Author: Secretan, Roger
  - "Consultations Donnees A La Mairie De Lille (France) Par Me Louis Selosse Avec Le Concours De M. Jacquey" [Consultation Given at the City Hall of Lille (France) ], 1927 (Box 39, Folder 6 item 1)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-188, Author: Selosse, Louis
  - "War of 1914-1918", 1927 (Box 39, Folder 6 item 2)
  - "Occupation of Lille (France) by the Germans", 1927 (Box 39, Folder 6 item 3)
  - "Le Proces de la Societe des Nations" ["The Proceedings of the League of Nations"], 1923 ca. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-189, Author: Semenoff, Marc
  - "Le Regime Nouveau des Traites Internationalaux" ["The New System of International Treaties"], 1925 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    Subject: French. Previous folder number: J-4-190, Author: Sevens, Constantin Louis